angelfoodministries.com 2011-06-15

# Privacy Policy - Angel Food Ministries

Angel Food Ministries’ Online Privacy Policy outlines the collection, use, and disclosure of all customer and host site information that may be collected by Angel Food Ministries’ websites. Angel Food Ministries collects your personal information in order to better serve you with the products and services that Angel Food Ministries offers. 

## What Information do we collect? 

When visiting an Angel Food Ministries’ website, information may be collected in one or more of the following ways:

  * When ordering or registering on an Angel Food Ministries website, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your contact information. Contact information may include your name, e-mail address, mailing address, or phone number. 
  * Organization information may be collected when an organization is applying to be a host site. Organization information may include organizations name, e-mail address, mailing address, or phone number. This may also include contact information for the organization’s representative or representatives.
  * Demographic information may be collected when an organization is applying to be a host site.
  * When ordering, you may be asked for your credit card number or some other piece of financial information in order to secure payment for a product that Angel Food Ministries sells.
  * Our websites may be visited anonymously, but we may still collect information such as IP address, referrer information, or cookies.

## What do we use your information for?

Personal information is collected by Angel Food Ministries’ websites through the following:

  * Anonymous visitor information is collected from all visits, including IP address, browser, and referrer information and stored in cookies for assistance in tracking our online marketing efforts. Using cookies is a legitimate standard practice by many websites which is used to help identify the most popular or least popular parts of a website. Cookies may also be used to maintain sessions on portions of a website that requires a user to login or submit an order. Non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.
  * As is standard practice on many corporate websites, Angel Food Ministries’ websites use “cookies” to help us understand which parts of our websites are the most popular, where our visitors are going, and how much time they spend there. We also use cookies and other technologies to make sure that our online advertising is bringing customers to our products and services
  * Contact information is collected from general visitors who fill out our contact forms and transmitted to the selected party with the visitor’s full knowledge. 
  * “Referral” contact information, includes email addresses that are submitted through our online form in order to “tell a friend” about Angel Food.  These email addresses are treated contact information, including email address and subscription preferences, are collected via our “Refer a Friend” feature at <http://www.angelfoodministries.com/forwardtoafriend/>.  This information is used to send a one-time email, at which time these emails are deleted from our systems and not used again.
  * “Subscriber” contact information, including email address and subscription preferences, are collected via our “Subscribe to Updates” feature at [ http://www.angelfoodministries.com/subscribe/](http://www.angelfoodministries.com/subscribe/). This double-opt-in subscription system allows someone who has not ordered from Angel Food to receive updates, and users may unsubscribe from this free service at any time.
  * “Customer” contact information is collected from customers during the ordering process for the following: 
    * To send you an electronic receipt and order pickup reminder.
    * To be stored in our secure database.
    * To be used for future contact, which the user can opt out of at any time.
    * To be sent to host sites in order to service you. Host sites may use this information in various ways, and Angel Food Ministries takes no responsibility for their use of your private information. Please contact your selected host site if you have any concerns about their privacy policy.
  * During the ordering process, full customer payment information (e.g., credit card or debit card information) is collected from customers and is transmitted immediately to our merchant services provider, however this payment information is not stored in our database.  We do retain enough payment information to identify the card type and the last four digits and name on the card for Customer Care purposes, however this information is not adequate to perform further charges to your account.
  * “Applicant” contact information is collected during the application process, including contact, organization and demographic information. This information is collected and stored in our database for the purpose of verification and approval process.
  * “Host Site” information, including detailed contact information for the host site director, assistant host site director, pastor, mailing and physical address information and phone numbers are collected and maintained for all active host sites. 
  * All information collected, including email address and contact information, may be used to for the purpose of marketing Angel Food services, such as reminders and menu updates. 
  * Angel Food Ministries may utilize a 3rd party services for the purpose of sending emails, however these services are required to adhere to this privacy policy and not utilize your private information for any other purpose. 
  * Angel Food Ministries may release your information when it is appropriate to do so in order to comply with the law, enforce Angel Food Ministries’ site policy, or protect Angel Food Ministries’ or some other person’s or entity’s rights, property or safety. 
  * No information collected is ever transmitted to any other 3rd party for any other reason without express permission.

Ultimately, any information collected on an Angel Food Ministries website is used to improve our websites, better personalize your experience, improve Customer Care, process transactions, and send periodic emails or mailings.

## Opting Out

Depending on the source of the data, opting out of our communications may take several forms:

  * All emails will contain opt-out information at the bottom of the email, and all opt-out requests will be automatically processed within 24 hours.
  * "Referrals" need not opt-out, as their contact information is deleted from our system after their one-time email.
  * “Subscribers” may change their contact preferences or unsubscribe at any time from [ http://www.angelfoodministries.com/subscribe/](http://www.angelfoodministries.com/subscribe/)
  * “Customers” should contact their selected host site to have their contact information deleted, as this information is under the control of individual host sites.
  * “Applicants” should contact our Ministry Development department at 770-267-7015 to have their information removed from our system, should they decide not to become an active host site.
  * “Host Sites” who maintain an active status may not opt-out of communications from Angel Food Ministries, as these communications are an essential part of the ongoing host site communication process. To update or replace contact information, host sites may contact Customer Care at 770-267-7015 or log in to the host site backoffice at AngelNET.org to modify this information at any time.

## How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order, submit your contact information, or access your personal information.   
We offer the use of a secure server when placing an online order. All sensitive financial data (i.e. credit card information) is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway provider’s database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. Angel Food Ministries does not store any credit card data on its secure servers or databases. 

## California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Because Angel Food Ministries value your privacy, Angel Food Ministries has taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. Angel Food Ministries therefore well not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent if you live in the state of California.

## Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

Angel Food Ministries is in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act). It is not the intention of Angel Food Ministries to collection any information on users under the age of 13. Our websites, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years of age or older.

## Online Privacy Policy Only

This online privacy policy only applies to information collected through our websites only.

## Consent

You consent to Angel Food Ministries’ privacy policy by using our websites.  
Changes to our Privacy Policy

All changes made to Angel Food Ministries’ privacy policy will posted to [ http://www.angelfoodministries.com/privacy/](http://www.angelfoodministries.com/privacy/)

## Contact

You may contact Angel Food Ministries at:

P.O. Box 128   
Good Hope, Georgia 30641

| _This policy was last updated on February 20, 2009_ |   
---|---
